Finding Aid for the James B. Coover Collection of Bibliographic Catalogs, 1690-1994
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Bibliographic catalogs, 1690-1994, I.; Items 1-155
  - Gilhofer & Ranschburg (Vienna, Austria). Österreich und die Nachfolgestaaten: wertvolle Bücher und Handschriften aus der Bibliothek Alexander Fürst Dietrichstein, Nikolsburg; Literatur, Almanache, Theaterstücke, Porträts von Schauspielern, Dichtern und Musikern; Theaterszenen, Kostüme und 
    Additional title: Auktion LXI: Bibliothek Alexander Furst Dietrichstein, Nikolsburg …
    Vienna (Austria): Gilhofer & Ranschburg
    829 lots. Bound with Auktion LXI Schatzungspreise.
    Named collector(s): Dietrichstein, Alexander, Prince; Heymann, August
  - Leo Liepmannssohn (Firm). Autographen, darunter kostbare Stücke aus dem Goethe- und Schillerkreise: Versteigerung Mittwoch, den 23. Mai 1934 ... und Donnerstag, den 24. Mai 1934, 1934-05-23, 164 pages, 8 plates, some music (Box 4, Item 083)
    Additional title: Versteigerung 64
    774 lots. Prices sheet laid in.
  - Henning Oppermann (Basel, Switzerland) and Ulrico Hoepli (Milan, Italy). Autographen-Sammlung des Kammerherrn und russischen Gesandten Baron Karl von Knorring (1810-1870), der schriftliche Nachlass von Professor Dr. Paul Kristeller (1863-1931),: Stammbücher, Manuskripte, Briefsammlungen usw.: Versteigerung im Geschäftslokal der Firma Henning Oppermann, Basel (Schweiz), Freiestrasse 74, Montag, den 28. bis Mittwoch, den 30. Mai 1934, 1934-05-28, 121 pages (Box 4, Item 084)
    Additional title: Autographen: Sammlung des Baron Karl von Knorring (1810-1870), nebst wertvollen Stucken aus anderem Besitz, zusammen mit dem schriftlichen Nachlass von Professor Dr. Paul Kristeller (1863-1931) …
    Basel (Switzerland): Henning Oppermann (Basel, Switzerland) and Ulrico Hoepli (Milan, Italy)
    1171 lots. Auktionskatalog Nr. 437. Includes "Auftrage fur die Versteigerung der Autographensammlung Baron Karl von Knorring" and price list.
    Named collector(s): Knorring, Karl Von, Baron; Kristeller, Paul
  - H.P. Kraus (Firm). Musikbibliothek Joseph Proksch Prag: Musikliteratur, Frühdrucke, Instrumental- und Vokalmusik Erstausgaben, 1934-11-20, 88 pages, illustrations (Box 4, Item 085)
    Additional title: Musik Bibliothek Proksch Prag
    Vienna (Austria): H.P. Kraus (Firm)
    1717 lots.
    Named collector(s): Proksch, Joseph
  - Hodgson and Co.. Catalogue of valuable book comprising a twelfth century MS. On vellum, … also books on music, singing and dancing from the library of the late Sir John Stainer … including the works of Yonge, Morley, Lawes, Playford, Mace, Purcell, Blow and others, and works on the history of music, etc. which will be sold by auction by Messrs. Hodgson & Co. … Wednesday, December 5th, 1934 …, 1934-12-05, 62 pages (Box 4, Item 086)
    London (England): Hodgson and Co.
    957 lots. Stainer's, 636-768, priced in MS.
    Named collector(s): Stainer, John, 1840-1901
  - Gilhofer & Ranschburg (Vienna, Austria). Katalog 187: Porträts von Musikern: Komponisten, Virtuosen, Sängern, Schauspielern, Tanzern, Forderern und Freunden des Theaters und der Musik, in Schabkunst, Radierung, Kupferstich, Lithographie etc. nebst Autographen, 1935?, 57 pages (Box 4, Item 087)
    Vienna (Austria): Gilhofer & Ranschburg (Vienna, Austria)
    1988 lots.
  - Heinrich Hinterberger (Firm). Interessante Autographen: I. Musiker; II. Dichter, Schriftsteller, Gelehrte, Fursten, Militars, Staatsmanner, etc.; III. Nachtrag, darunter mehrere Dokumente von Prasidenten der USA. Katalog XX, 1937, 100 pages (Box 4, Item 088)
    Additional title: Katalog XX
    Vienna (Austria): Antiquariat H. Hinterberger
    881 lots.Prices fixed and printed.
  - Georges Andrieux (Firm). Livres anciens, romantiques et modernes. Dédicaces autographes de Vigny, Musset, Schumann, Sand, etc … à Franz Liszt. Musique - Partitions autographes., 1937-10-28, 64 pages (Box 4, Item 089)
    Paris (France): Georges Andrieux, printed by F. Paillart
    456 lots. Commissaire-priseur, Maurice Rheims; Expert pres les douanes Francaises: Georges Andrieux.
  - Sotheby & Co. (London, England). Catalogue of a selected portion of the well-known collection of old and rare music and books on music, the property of Godfrey E.P. Arkwright which will be sold by auction by Sotheby & Co, 1939-02-13, 64 pages (Box 4, Item 090)
    London (England): Sotheby & Co.
    295 lots.
    Named collector(s): Arkwright, G. E. P. (Godfrey Edward Pellew)
  - Joseffy, Carl. Musical library owned by Rafael Joseffy, 1853-1915: piano compositions, orchestral parts and scores. Catalog no. 1, 1941?, 8 pages (Box 4, Item 091)
    New York (N.Y.): Carl Joseffy
    Named collector(s): Joseffy, Rafael
  - Parke-Bernet Galleries. Incunabula including Aristophanes, 1498, Catholicon, circa 1470, Cicero, 1481, Entymologium magnum graecum, 1499, A fine collection of French armorial bindings …., 1941-11-26, 145 pages, plates (Box 4, Item 092)
    Additional title: Incunabula - Early and later manuscripts - [etc.]… from the libraries of … together with the musical autograph letters and manuscripts … assembled by the late … auction sale November 26 [-27]
    New York (N.Y.): Parke-Bernet Galleries
    592 lots.
    Named collector(s): Cole, Edwin R.; Murray, Howard; Palmer, Harold; Kane, John P.; Riesenfeld, Hugo
  - Hodgson and Co.. Catalogue of miscellaneous books ... together with the music library of the late Benjamin J. Dale, F.R.a.M. and the remaining portion of that of the late G.E.P. Arkwright, Esq.: comprising orchestral, instrumental and vocal scores, mostly bound in half morocco; books on the history and art of music, etc., which will be sold by auction by Messrs. Hodgson & Co. ... on Thursday, August 2nd, 1945 and following day, 1945-08-02, 43 pages (Box 4, Item 093)
    London (England): Hodgson & Co.
    648 lots. Dale's properties lots 277-322, Arkwright's 323-445. These sections priced in pencil. No. 10 of 1944-45.
    Named collector(s): Dale, Benjamin; Arkwright, G. E. P. (Godfrey Edward Pellew)
  - Martin Breslauer, Inc.. Bibliography & palaeography: The science of librarianship and book collecting, illustrated by an unusually rich collection of catalogue of books and MSS. of bibliographical value; history and practice of printing; a miscellany of books on many subjects including - book-bindings, Casanova, economics, literary forgeries and mystifications, Goethe, Golden Cockerel Press, law, painting and engraving, philosophy, Reformation, science, medicine and allied subjects, Sixteenth century, printing, etc., etc., 1949, 71 pages (Box 4, Item 094)
    Additional title: Catalogue No. 68: Bibliography: Books on books and manuscripts, history and practice of printing, an unusual collection of library catalogues and description of libraries. A Miscellany of books on various subjects
    London (England): Martin Breslauer, printed by Harding & Curtis
    Not in Coover's donation list.
  - Parke-Bernet Galleries. Sixty-six XVII-XX century Italian musical manuscripts fron the Natale Gallini collection. Public auction sale May 3, by order of the present Italian owner, 1949-05-03, 34 pages (Box 4, Item 095)
    Additional title: Sale number 1065
    66 lots. Priced in pencil. Contains manuscript annotations.
    Named collector(s): Gallini, Natale
  - Parke-Bernet Galleries. Rare books & manuscripts: block book leaves, Persian miniatures … Toscanini's autograph ms. of his arrangement of The Star spangled banner … and autograph music manuscripts by Johann Strauss, 1952-12-09, 193 pages (Box 4, Item 096)
    Additional title: Rare books & manuscripts: important palleographic specimens to valuable modern works …
    755 lots. Sale Number 1389.
    Named collector(s): Cohn, J. C.; Simon,, Elsie; Goodwin, Walter; White, Wallace H.; Greenhill, Harold; Sproul, George D.
  - City Book Auction (New York, N.Y.). Sale no. 624; Art and music; ceramics, furniture, prints, ballet & dance, allied subjects; Sale no. 625; Americana, 1954-02-19, 74 pages (Box 4, Item 097)
    Additional title: Sale no. 625: Americana
    New York (N.Y.): City Book Auction
    1098 lots.
  - Parke-Bernet Galleries. Autographs, books, documents, musical scores, including important letters written by George Washington and John Adams, a manuscript score by Johannes Brahms signed "Kreisler, jun.", a musical specimen by Chopin, … property of a New York Lady … and other owners …, 1954-02-23, 100 pages (Box 4, Item 098)
    Additional title: Autograph letters, manuscripts, documents of historical, literary and musical interest …
    New York (N.Y.): Parke-Benet Galleries
    349 lots. Music items, inter alia. Prices in pencil.
    Named collector(s): Mylnarski, Doris Kenyon; Pond, James B.
  - Otto Harrassowitz (Firm). Antiquarian Sale books & scores: Special Music Catalog No. 6, 1955?, 38 pages (Box 4, Item 099)
    Additional title: Special Music Catalog No.6
    Wiesbaden (Germany): Otto Harrassowitz
    Not in Coover's donation list. Featuring the library of Albert Mayer-Reinach.
    Named collector(s): Mayer-Reinach, Albert
  - Haus der Bücher (Basel, Switzerland). Schlossbibliothek des Freiherrn von Berstett (1769-1837): Bibliothek eines Musikwissenschaftlers; und Beiträge aus den Sammlungen zweier schweizer. Hochschullehrer, sowie aus anderem Besitz, 1957-04-11, 127 pages (Box 4, Item 100)
    Additional title: Bibliothek Freiherr von Berstett: Bibliothek eines Musikgelehrten…Basel. 11. und 12. April 1957
    Basel (Switzerland): Haus der Bücher/ L'art ancien.
    1172 lots. Auktion XXVIII.
    Named collector(s): Berstett, August, Freiherr
  - Lucien Dorbon (Firm). Théâtre, musique, danse: livres provenant en majeure partie de la bibliothèque de J.-G. Prod'homme. Catalogue 639, 1958, 80 pages (Box 4, Item 101)
    Additional title: Catalogue 639
    Paris (France): Lucien Dorbon (Firm)
    1625 lots (many more items). Catalogue Lucien Dorbon.
    Named collector(s): Prod'homme, J.-G. (Jacques-Gabriel)
  - Sotheby & Co. (London, England). Catalogue of printed books and music, comprising music and books on music and musicians, with some manuscripts, the property of ... E. J. Dent, the property of ... J. B. Trend, art books, bibliography, works on Chinese and European ceramics, limited editions published by the Bibliophile Society of Boston, well-bound library sets,, etc., the property of T. Job, the property of the late Ivan Traugott, Esq. of Stockholm, the property of J. O. Duveen, esq., and the property of the late Mrs. P. L. Agnew, a small collection of books on alchemy, the property of Walter Scott-Elliot, Esq., Talbot Rice's Pencil of nature, 1844, the first book illustrated with photographs, a run of the Oriental Translation Fund publications, etc., ... books on Australia …, 1958-01-20, 116 pages (Box 4, Item 102)
    Additional title: Catalogue of printed books and music with a few manuscripts comprising the property of the late Professor E.J. Dent, ... J.B. Trend, ... T. Job, ... Ivan Traugott of Stockholm, ... J.O. Duveen, esq., and the property of the late Mrs. P.L. Agnew …
    903 lots. List of prices with buyers' names bound in.
    Named collector(s): Dent, Edward J.; Trend, J. B. (John Brande)
  - Art Ancien S.A., Haus der Bücher (Basel, Switzerland). Umfangreiche Bibliothek aus altem Zürcher Familienbesitz: erster Teil: Bibliographie, Bodonidrucke, antike Philosophie, Genealogie, Heraldik etc. (dabei Numismatik, Sphragistik, Turnierwesen, Fechten, Rittertum etc.), modernee Bücher (dabei Luxusdrucke und einige Kunstbücher), Kostüme, Varia, Geographie, Reisen, Atlanten, Ansichtenwerke, Karten und Veduten (mit Beiträgen aus anderem Besitz, u.a. Bücher aus der Bibliothek Arthur Schopenhauers); Musik und Musikwissenschaft: eine bedeutende Sammlung älterer und neuer theoretischer und praktischer Musik aus dem Besitze eines Musikers und zweier Musikgelehrter ...: Versteigerung unter Leitung der Gantbeamtung der Stadt Basel, im Erasmushuas, Haus der Bücher AG, Basel ... am Dienstag, den 9. Juni und Mittwoch, den 10. Juni 1959 durch L'Art ancien S.A., Buch- und Kunstantiquariat ... Haus der Bücher AG., Antiquariat, 1959-06-09, 144 pages (Box 4, Item 103)
    Additional title: Zurcher Bibliothek I. Teil … Musikwissenschaft
    Zurich (Switzerland), Basel (Switzerland): Art Ancien / Haus der Bücher
    1385 lots. Auktion XXXI. Music, lots 246-710 priced.
  - Hodgson and Co.. Catalogue of the music library of Ernest Newman (dec'd), removed from Tadworth, Surrey: comprising ... full orchestral scores, vocal and instrumental music ...; books on music ...; also classics, art, literature, etc. ...: which will be sold by auction by Messrs. Hodgson & Co. (Sidney Hodgson and Wilfrid B. Hodgson) at their rooms, No. 115 Chancery Lane, London, W.C.2 ... on Thursday, December 10th, 1959 and following day, 1959-12-10, 39 pages (Box 4, Item 104)
    Additional title: Catalogue of the music library formed by Ernest Newman
    578 lots. All lots with buyer's names and prices fetched in MS. "No. 3 of 1959-60."
    Named collector(s): Newman, Ernest
  - J.A. Stargardt (Firm). Autographen aus verschiedenem besitz … Auktion am 17. Mai 1960 in Marburg. Katalog 548, 1960-05-17, 182 pages, 5 plates (Box 4, Item 105)
    Additional title: Katalog 548
    Marburg (Germany): J.A. Stargardt (Firm)
    Music, lots 440-586.
  - Parke-Bernet Galleries. American and foreign autographs of great historical significance over six centuries: by eminent statesmen, authors, scientists, doctors, philosophers and musicians: collected by the late Mr. Max Thorek, Chicago, Illinois: sold by order of the executors of his estate: public auction, Tursday, November 15 ... Wednesday, November 16 [1960] …, 1960-11-15, 162 pages, plates (Box 5, Item 106)
    Additional title: Renowned autograph collection of the late Dr. Max Thorek
    640 lots. Priced throughout. "The following are Parke-Bernet catalogues, mostly used by some prospective bidders; though priced."
    Named collector(s): Thorek, Max
  - Hodgson and Co.. Catalogue of books and music comprising books and autograph letters sold on behalf of the Keats-Shelley Memorial Association, including Rowlandson's Loyal Volunteers, and an interesting holograph MS. by Walter Savage Landor, Fine books with coloured plates, collected editions of Restoration Dramatists, books on Mediaeval history and antiquities, the property of the Athenaeum, Also, the important music collection formed by Edward Holmes (dec'd.), of the firm of Walsh, Holmes & Co., Ltd., including a collection of music by Corelli, Geminiani, Handel, Vivaldi and others, published by James Walsh and bound in 7 volumes, Bickhams's Musical Entertainer, a set of the Treìsor des Pianistes in 21 vols., first editions of Beethoven, Couperin, Mozart, Schubert and others, facsmilies of autograph scores, Books on the history and theory of music, musical instruments, opera, theatre, etc., Collections of song books, musical miscellany, 6 vols., 1729, Universal Harmony, 1745, Calliope, engravings, portraits and play-bills relating to Madame Vestris and to the Vauxhall Gardens, an extensive collection of Victorian popular song and dance music, Interesting manuscripts and autograph letters, etc. which will be sold by auction by Messrs. Hodgson & Co. ... on Thursday, March 23rd, 1961 and following day, 1961-03-21, 44 pages (Box 5, Item 107)
    585 lots. Holmes properties, lots 326-585, with buyers' names and prices fetched in MS. No. 6 of 1961-62.
    Named collector(s): Holmes, Edward
  - Hodgson and Co.. Catologue of books including books from a country house library and other properties, comprising interesting sixteenth and seventeenth century books … music and books on music, the property of Harold Reeves (dec'd.) and others ...: which will be sold by auction by Messrs. Hodgson & Co. ... at their rooms, 115 Chancery Lane, W.C.2 on Thursday, May 18th, 1961 and following day, 1961-05-18, 40 pages (Box 5, Item 108)
    Additional title: No. 8 of 1960-61
    643 lots. Reeves' lots 504-62, priced.
    Named collector(s): Reeves, Harold
  - V. A. Heck (Firm). Musikbibliothek Professor Julius von Schlosser (Liste 237), 1962-01, 62 pages (Box 5, Item 109)
    Additional title: Liste 237
    Vienna (Austria): Antiquariat V. A. Heck
    Named collector(s): Schlosser, Julius, Ritter von
  - Perre, Paul van der. Importante bibliothèque musique et musicologie: ouvrages variés anciens & modernes, éditions originales, beaux-arts, bibliographie, sciences, livres illustrés, voyages, topographie, divers, reliures, gravures: vente publique au Palais des Beaux-arts de Bruxelles, Jeudi 22, Vendredi 23 et Samedia 24 Mars 1962, 1962-03-22, 141 pages (Box 5, Item 110)
    Additional title: Importante bibliothèque musicale et libres varies
    Brussels (Belgium): Palais des beaux-arts (Brussels, Belgium)
    1336 lots. Music & Theatre, lots 1-657.
  - Wiener Antiquariat Ingo Nebehay. Autographe berühmter Musiker. Liste 19, 1966-04, 76 pages (Box 5, Item 111)
    Additional title: Liste 19
    Vienna (Austria): Wiener Antiquariat Ingo Nebehay
    904 lots. 2 volumes bound in 1.
    Bound with: Autograph beruhmter Dichter und Musiker, Liste 34 (January 1969)
  - Dr. Ernst Hauswedell (Firm). Musik Autographen, Noten, Bücher: Versteigerung in Hamburg, Montag, den 23. Mai 1966, 1966-05-23, 68 page (Box 5, Item 112)
    Additional title: Auktion 146 (Antiquariatskatalog 214)
    Hamburg (Germany): Dr. Ernst Hauswedell (Firm); In Verbindung mit dem Musikantiquariat Hans Schneider
    728 lots,
  - Wantagh Rare Book Company. Americana Catalogue no. 2-4, 1967-1972, Nos.2-14, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Item 113)
    Wantagh (N.Y.): Wantagh Rare Book Company
    Catalogue no. 4 is subtitled: Abraham Lincoln and the War between the States.
  - Antiquariaat Antiqua (Amsterdam). Antiqua: old and new books (Newsletters, Catalogues and Lists), 1967-1973?, 7 volumes bound in 1 (Box 5, Item 114)
    Amsterdam (Netherlands): Antiquariaat Antiqua
    Contains: Music-newsletter no. 8: Musical literature -- Music book list no. 10: Musicology -- Catalogue no. 19: Musicology -- Catalogue no. 14: Musical literature -- Catalogue no. 17: Books on musicology (2 copies) -- Book list no. 14: Musicology; Theater
  - Chapman, Catherine Weeks. Printed collections of polyphonic music owned by Ferdinand Columbus, 1968, pages 31-84 (Box 5, Item 115)
    New York (N.Y.): Journal of the American Musicological Society
    Named collector(s): Colón, Fernando
  - University of Kentucky. Libraries. Alfred Cortot Collection at the University of Kentucky Libraries, 1970, 18 pages, illustrations (Box 5, Item 116)
    Additional title: University of Kentucky library notes, v. 1, no. 3
    Lexington (Ky.): University of Kentucky Libraries
    Named collector(s): Cortot, Alfred
  - Nanki Ongaku Bunko. Catalogue of rare books and notes [i.e. scores]. The Ohki Collection, 1970, 60 pages (Box 5, Item 117)
    Additional title: Zōsho mokuroku, kichō shiryō
    Tokyo (Japan): Nanki Music Library
    Named collector(s): Ohki Collection
  - Hôtel Drouot. XVIIIe siècles), J.S. Bach, M.A. Charpentier, L.N. Clerambault, Dussek, Haydn, Lully, Mozart, Pleyel, etc., Livres illustrés modernes ... Autographes …, 1971-12-13, no page numbers (Box 5, Item 118)
    120 lots.
  - Christie, Manson & Woods. Autograph letters of George Frideric Handel and Charles Jennens: the property of the Earl Howe: which will be sold at auction by Christie, Manson & Woods, at their Great Rooms, London, on Wednesday, July 4, 1973, 1973-07-04, 28 pages, [9] pages of plates: facsimiles (Box 5, Item 119)
    London (England): Christie, Manson & Woods
    Named collector(s): Handel, George Frideric; Jennens, Charles; Howe, Edward Richard Assheton Penn Curzon, Earl
  - Ader, Picard, Tajon. Manuscrits musicaux, autographes et collection d'affiches: dont la vente aux enchères publiques aura lieu Hotel Drouot Salle no. 8, le vendredi 14 décembre 1973 …, 1973-12-14, 60 unnumbered pages (Box 5, Item 120)
    Additional title: Precieux manuscrits de Jacques Offenbach et autographes
    178 lots. Commissaire-priseur, Etienne Ader, Antoine Ader, Jean-Louis Picard, Jacques Tajan, assistes de Michel Castaing, Denise Rousseau; pour les autographes, Maison Charavay; Pour les affiches, Denise Rousseau.
    Named collector(s): Offenbach, Jacques
  - Henkel, Robert E.. Rare and scarce sheet music. List #600, 1974?, 14 pages (Box 5, Item 121)
    Jersey City (N.J.): Robert E. Henkel
    Typescript catalogs.
    Bound with: Rare & scare sheet music, List #300 (12 pages) -- Psalms & sacred songs (3 pages) -- Music (4 pages)
  - Hôtel Drouot. Autographes et documents historiques dont la vente aux enchères publiques aura lieu Hotel Drouot salle no. 10, le jeudi 21 novembre 1974, à 14 heures 30, par le ministère de Etienne Ader [and others]; assistés de Michel Castaing, 1974-11-21, 71 unnumbered pages, numerous plates and facsimiles (Box 5, Item 122)
    Additional title: Collection Sacha Guitry
    Paris (France): Ader, Picard, Tajan
    102 lots.
    Named collector(s): Guitry, Sacha
  - Ader, Picard, Tajan. Collection musicale Marc Pincherle dont la vente auc enchères publiques aura lieu Hotel Drouot…les 3, 4, et 5 Mars 1975, 1975-03-03, Pages unnumbered (Box 5, Item 123)
    1047 lots. Michael Castaing (Expert). Many prices in pencil.
    Named collector(s): Pincherle, Marc
  - Antiquariaat Frits Knuf. Musicology: the libraries of Dr. Paul Cronheim, Dr. Rudolf Mengelberg and Max Vredenburg, 1976, 2 volumes in 1, 46 pages and 28 pages (Box 5, Item 124)
    Additional title: Catalogus 121
    Buren (Netherlands): Antiquariaat Frits Knuf
    872 and 373 lots.
    Named collector(s): Cronheim, Paul; Mengelberg, Rudolf; Vredenburg, Max
  - Sotheby Parke Bernet Inc.. Fine musical instruments, the property of various owners, including The Brooklyn Museum, The Carl E. Tanneicz Trust, sold by order of Old Kent Bank and Trust Co., 1977-04-05, 52 unnumbered pages, colored plates (Box 5, Item 125)
    Additional title: Sale number 3969
    New York (N.Y.): Sotheby Parke Bernet Inc.
  - Laurin, Guilloux, Buffetaud, Tailleur (Firm). Autographes musicaux. I. Manuscrits et lettres de compositeurs II. Manuscrits et lettres de Paul Dukas III. Partitions et lettres provenant de Ricardo Vines, 1977-06-20, 179 pages, many full-page facsimiles (Box 5, Item 126)
    Paris (France): Laurin, Guilloux, Buffetaud, Tailleur (Firm)
    Decorative
    Named collector(s): Dukas, Paul; Vines, Ricardo
  - J. A. Stargardt (Firm). Auction…29 and 30 November, 1977. III. Musik., 1977-11-29, Pages 190-256, with plates (Box 5, Item 127)
    Marburg (Germany): J. A. Stargardt (Firm)
    lots 644-920. Title of full catalog: Autographen aus allen Gebieten: Auktion am 29. und 30. November 1977 im Marburg, Kurhotel Ortenberg
  - Haus der Bücher (Basel, Switzerland). Musik: Autographen, Musikwissenschaft, Praktische Musik, Zeitschriften. Katalog 788, 1978-01, 86 pages (Box 5, Item 128)
    Additional title: Katalog 788
    Basel (Switzerland): Haus der Bücher
    1127 lots. Priced.
  - Sotheby Parke Bernet & Co.. Catalogue of the highly important Toulouse-Philidor collection: of manuscript and printed music and other valuable manuscripts and printed books ... which will be sold by auction by Sotheby Parke Bernet & Co. ... Day of sale, Monday 26th June, 1978, 1978-06-26, 87 pages, [4] pages of plates (Box 5, Item 129)
    Additional title: Highly important Toulouse-Philidor collection
    London (England): Sotheby Parke Bernet & Co.
    Bound with other content, a mix of originals and photocopies compiled by James Coover.
    Named collector(s): Philidor, Andre; Toulouse, Louis-Alexandre de Bourbon, comte de